spoilers spoilers never
change the infinite spoiler train
doesn't stop for anyone as we've just
had a bunch of info drop on the upcoming
Fallout Magic the Gathering crossover
set here's a brief overview before we go
over all of the cards that were spoiled
there are going to be four new Fallout
themed Commander decks each coming in
with about 40 new cards each and just
like the Doctor Who set there are going
to be collector boosters which contain
blinged out versions of the commander
cards including borderless Vault booy
cards pit boy framed cards serialized
Bubblehead cards along with foils surge
foils and other extended Arts let's
quickly go over the decks first up we
have Scrappy survivors which is led by
dog me ever loyal dog me is a three
minor Nia 33 legendary dog with an ETB
of mil five cards then return an aura or
equipment card from your graveyard to
your hand and whenever Enchanted or
equipped creature attacks create a junk
token now junk tokens are an artifact
that you can tap and sacrifice it to
Exile the top card of your library and
you may cast it this turn activate only
as a sorcery effectively granting us a
free impulse effect so the theme of this
deck is based around auras equipments
and survivors with the Wizards of the
Coast team saying they wanted to have a
deck that shows how you the player in
the Fallout games level up with perks
and skills and one of those perks we got
to see was idolize idolize is a two Mana
aura that says enchant creature
Enchanted creature has whenever this
creature attacks alone it gets plus X
Plus X until end of turn where X is the
number of non-land permanence you
control effectively it's a super exalted
effect it also reminds me of All That
Glitters the next deck we have is
science finally an energy based
Commander science is helmed by Dr
Madison Lee Dr Lee is a three minor J
Sky legendary human scientist a 2 three
that says whenever you cast an artifact
spell you get an energy of course energy
is an alternative resource that was last
seen back in cadesh Dr Lee has three
abilities tap pay one energy Target
creature gets plus one plus 0 gains
trample and haste until end of turn next
tap and pay three energy draw a card
and finally Tap and Pay five energy
return Target artifact card from your
graveyard to the battlefield tapped in
this deck you also get Rex cyberhound
from Fallout New Vegas a three Mana
aorus 22 legendary robot dog that says
whenever Rex deals combat damage to a
player they Mill two cards and you get
two energy Rex has pay two energy to
Exile a creature card in a graveyard and
put a brain counter on it activate only
as a sorcery Rexx has all activated
abilities of all cards in Exile with a
brain counter on them Rex is very
similar to cards like Patchwork crawler
and experiment CR which both see very
Fringe play but the fact that Rex is a
repeatable source of energy generation I
wonder if he'll make the cut in any case
if you haven't already make sure to pick
up your Aether work Marvels or gantes
ather heart as it seems like a
no-brainer in this deck next up we have
hail SE
led by Caesar legion's emperor a four
Manor Manu legendary human Soldier a 44
that says whenever you attack you may
sacrifice another creature when you do
choose two create two one one red and
white Soldier creature tokens with haste
that are tapped and attacking you draw a
card and lose one life and Caesar deals
damage equal to the number of creature
tokens you control to Target opponent
this is an extremely powerful card not
only does this this ability trigger
whenever you attack meaning you can play
Caesar and immediately attack with
something else and get this ability to
trigger the ability also fuels its own
cost it generates you card advantage and
you can output some serious damage the
Halo Caesar deck is touted as your
typical Army soldier deck it's going to
be interesting to see what other new
cards we can get to help further this
theme one of the cards that was shown
off was Gary clone a two Mana 13 human
citizen with Squad 2 a returning
mechanic from the Warhammer 40K decks
you can pay an additional two Mana as
many times as you like when you cast
this card if you do create that many
copies and whenever Gary clone attacks
each creature under your control named
Gary clone gets plus one plus 0 until
end of turn Gary seems to go perfectly
well with the recently released nanog
Gene conversions from the Doctor Who set
next we have mutant Menace probably my
favorite deck of the bunch led by the
wise Moth Man a four Manor salai insect
mutant a 33 that says flying whenever
the wise Moth Man etbs or attacks each
player gets a rad counter we'll come
back to rad counters in a
second and whenever one or more nonland
cards are milled put a plus one plus one
counter on each of up to X Target
creatures where X is the number of
nonland cards milled this way so rad
counters AKA radiation would obviously
make an appearance in this set and this
is what the mutant Menace is focused on
radiation radiation says at the
beginning of your first main phase if
you have any route counters Mill that
many cards for each nonland card mil
this way you lose one life and A rad
counter so radiation is something that
naturally wears off over time but if you
get too much of it you just might end up
dying to it and MZ man's second ability
goes perfectly well with this new card
feral ghoul a three minor black zombie
mutant a 2 two with Menace that says
whenever another creature you control
dies put a plus one plus1 counter on
feral ghoul when feral ghoul dies each
opponent gets a number of rad counters
equal to its power I can't wait to combo
this card and get it to 100 power and
zap everybody with a deadly dose of
radiation and if I can't do it with
feral ghoul I can't wait to do it with
this next card rad storm a four Mana
blue instant that simply says storm
proliferate move aside all of history
all at once here's my new favorite
minimal text card poison lovers Rejoice
you just got your new combo kill card
don't forget you can also proliferate
energy loyalty counters law counters and
plenty of other relevant counters too
next we have intelligence Bubblehead a
three minor artifact that Taps for a
minor of any color and you can pay five
and tap it to draw cards equal to the
number of bubbleheads you control so in
Fallout bubbleheads were items you could
find throughout the world that you could
pick up to increase one of seven stat
points known as special strength
perception endurance Charisma
intelligence agility and luck so we can
expect at least six more bubbleheads to
appear during the spoiler season in
January it will be interesting to see if
they're all minor rocks with abilities
stapled onto them or if some of them are
going to be something else like
equipment or standard
artifacts next we have a crazy piece of
removal in the form of Vats a four Mana
black instant that has Split Second
meaning nobody can respond to it except
for Manor abilities and turn morph cards
face up choose any number of Target
creatures with equal toughness destroy
the chosen creatures obviously this card
is excellent at killing tokens or Gary
clones and even typo decks like goblins
or elves who usually have have
symmetrical power and toughness effects
meaning a lot of those cards are likely
to die to the single piece of removal
next there's Vault 101 birthday party a
four minor white Saga that has three
chapters chapter one create a one one
white human solder token and a food
chapter 2 and three put an aura or
equipment card from your graveyard or
hand into play and attach it the
designers have confirmed that there will
be a number of sagas that tell the
stories of different vaults from across
fallout's history as far as this one
goes being able to cheat something like
ozi conscription or argentum armor into
play and attach it for free shouldn't be
overlooked next we got a look at the
first lot of Vault booy alternate art
cards there are nine in total and here
are the first five that have been
spoiled these can only be found in
collector boosters so we've got soul
ring Arcane signate Crucible of Worlds
Wasteland and command Tower Alpha
deathclaw is a six golgari 66 with
Menace and trample when it etbs or
becomes monstrous destroy Target
permanent and for seven Mana it has
monstrosity 4 monstrosity is an ability
you can pay at instant speed and that
creature gains a number of plus one
plus1 counters on it equal to the number
next to the monstrosity keyword if you
ask me this seems like a tiny bit of an
upgrade to our Lord and savior colossal
dread Moore if this bad boy resolves at
worst you're getting a two for one and
if it survives a turn you may even get a
three for one this is a fantastic card
speaking of fantastic cards we have nuca
colola vending machine a three minor
artifact with pay one tap create a food
token and whenever you sacrific the food
create a tapped treasure token you are
not going to believe this but I think
vending machine has finally broken
Academy manufactur and KCI it's worth
noting though that this is not infinite
with just just Academy manufacturer by
itself as its replacement effect and the
three tokens it will create will come
into play tapped two so you'll need
something like KCI or something as
simple as paragan took in order to go
infinite next we have Mr House president
and CEO a fan favorite from Fallout New
Vegas Mr house is a three Mana muu 04
legendary human that says whenever you
roll a four or higher create a 33
colorless robot artifact creature token
if you rolled a six or higher instead
create that token and a treasure token
and pay four and tap roll a six-sided
dice plus an additional six-sided dice
for each Mana from Treasure spent to
activate this ability Mr house is our
first worthwhile dice rolling Commander
that can generate a ton of value
generating Treasures isn't that hard so
making full use of their second ability
is easy but don't forget you can make
even more more use out of the cards from
infinity and boulders gate the three
metallic dragons brass copper and gold
all r d20s as well as a number of other
cards from the set and don't forget
about Barbarian class too also there's
dice rolling mechanics from Infinity so
Cosmo and Friends definitely have a home
here our last preview card is a really
nice stacked piece that I can't wait to
try out over encumbered a two Manor Aura
enchant opponent when over encumbered
enters the battlefield Enchanted
opponent creates a clue a food and a
junk token at the beginning of combat on
Enchanted opponent's turn that player
May pay one for each artifact they
control if they don't creatures can't
attack this combat you already know how
much I love Pillow for and not only that
players having an abundance of artifacts
isn't out of the question anyway if you
can find a way to flicker this Aura it's
likely no one will be able to attack you
for the rest of the game
to wrap up previews we got shown some of
the best full art lands to date we got
five Vault dweller lands that look
amazing as well as five isometric lands
that throw back to the previous old
school versions of the
game and that about does it that's
everything we know about the upcoming
Fallout set that's dropping in March
next year official previews start in
January which is right about the time
ravener remastered releases and well you
know what they said
he